Nicholas Thomson

Brooklyn, NY 11213 | 415-859-0848 | nicholasgraythomson@gmail.com Github | Medium | Personal Website

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming, with a background as an Assistant Editor at Penguin Random House. Possess strong skills in editing, design, and project management that help tech companies build beautiful, responsive applications. A life spent learning has led me to many interesting places, including a cat circus in Moscow, where I was living one summer and studying Russian.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Orchid - Github | Demo

A Spotify-like app designed for classical music

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Accessed the Spotify API using the rSpotify gem to allow users to play songs in-browser
- Built and seeded a database using the Open Opus API to provide users with an encyclopedic collection of data
- Employed Material UI to style components for a clean, modern look

Open Chessame - Site | Github | Demo

An app that allows users to improve their chess openings

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Built a dynamic database including user info, openings, and games, which allows users to view nested data.
- Accessed the Youtube API to provide video instruction on opening moves.
- Employed Material UI to style components for a stunning in-browser experience.

Beanies, Baby! - Github | Demo

An e-commerce site, which allows users to shop for Beanie Babies.

- Used RESTful routing on both the client and server sides to create an easy-to-use cart to hold purchases.
- Deployed a Sinatra back end with a SQL database to hold product information.
- Built a log-in system with validation on the Sinatra backend to confirm a user's identity.
- Used Semantic UI to style components for an eye-catching look.

EXPERIENCE

Penguin Random House

Alfred A. Knopf New York, NY **Assistant Editor** 08/2018 - 2021

- Edited books by both Knopf and Pantheon authors with a focus on style, content, and grammatical detail.
- Wrote compelling, engaging copy, which was used for in-house marketing, on Amazon, and the jacket.

Penguin Random House

New York, NY

Alfred A. Knopf **Editorial Assistant**

• Assistant to Vice President and Executive Editor

10/2014 - 07/2018

- Served as the point of contact for authors during the editing and production processes.
- Collaborated with literary agents, designers, legal consultants, publicists, and production staff to ensure that deadlines were met and the author's vision was supported.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2021 - 08/2021

University of Chicago

Chicago, IL 06/2011

B.A. in Philosophy